umpquabank.com 2005-04-05

# Umpqua Bank - Privacy

As your financial services partner, Umpqua Bank understands that your trust in us is our most important asset. In order to preserve that trust, we want you to clearly understand what information we collect and how we use it. 

To give customers effective and convenient access to a broad range of financial products and services, we use technology to manage and maintain customer information. This notice describes the Privacy Policy and practices followed by Umpqua Bank and our affiliates. It also explains what types of customer information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it. Please note that this Privacy Policy supersedes any prior policy that we have issued. 

**Collecting Customer Information.**  
Umpqua Bank collects only relevant information about customers that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you (customer information) that is "nonpublic." Nonpublic personal information is information about you that we obtain in connection with providing a financial product or service to you. The customer information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources: 

**Application Information.**  
We retain personal information from any application you submit for deposit accounts, Electronic Fund Transfers (EFT) services, loans or other Bank services. This includes information such as name, address, social security number, employment and financial status, and credit history. 

**Your Transactions.**  
We retain the transaction information any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, transactions through Internet Banking, over the phone or at a branch. The transaction information includes your account number, date, amount, location of the transaction and any other pertinent information. 

**Credit and Marketing Information.**  
When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you, and we may use it to evaluate future account service requests. From time to time, we also obtain demographic household information about customers and potential customers from marketing information firms. 

**Online.**  
We obtain information online when you visit our website www.umpquabank.com. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online application, Internet banking transaction or information you send to us by e-mail. 

**Sharing Customer Information.**  
In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our affiliates and third-party service providers. We only share information with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices, and greater convenience. Information we may have about former customers is generally only shared or disclosed if necessary to enforce or administer an account or as required by law. 

**Sharing Information with Our Bank Affiliates.**  
We may share personal information (such as name, address, account number) and account information (such as type of accounts, account balances, transaction history) with our affiliates so that they can serve you more efficiently. Our affiliates maintain the same privacy standards as the Bank. 

**Sharing Information with Third-Party Service Providers.**  
In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers, including data processing companies, check, ATM, and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, insurance companies, collection agencies, credit reporting agencies and financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the customer information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information with third-party service providers depending on the specific services provided: 

  * Personal information (name, address and account number) 
  * Account information (type of accounts, account balances and transaction history) 
  * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations and type of transaction) 

We do not share your account numbers with independent third-party marketers offering their own products and services. While we may assist in offering financial products and services of our affiliates or other financial service providers, we control the customer information used to make these offers. 

**Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted.**  
We may share your customer information in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency or regulatory authority, or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account, such as in response to a request issued by a merchant or business necessary to affect, administer, or enforce a transaction that you request or authorize in connection with the servicing or processing of a financial product or service, or to maintain or service your account with us. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate. 

We do not share medical information provided as part of insurance applications or claims, except for the purposes you have authorized. 

**Protecting Information**

 **Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards.**  
We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that customer information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees and contractors are permitted access to customer information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees and contractors have access to such customer information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees and contractors are required to respect customer privacy. No one except our employees and contractors has access to the Bank’s computer system and records storage. The Bank has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your customer information as we employ new technology in the future. 

**Information Integrity Measures.**  
Umpqua Bank works hard to ensure that the customer information we maintain is complete and accurate. We have procedures and processes for updating our customer information as well as removing old, outdated information. We have measures in place to protect the integrity of customer information such as maintaining back-up copies of account data in the event of power outages or other business interruptions. We use computer virus detection and eradication software and employ other technical means (known as "Firewalls") to protect against unauthorized computer entry into systems containing customer information. 

**Online Privacy Protection.**  
At our website (www.umpquabank.com), you may apply for accounts and services, and you may communicate with us via e-mail. To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. The application information we accept online and our Internet Banking service relies on industry standard "Secure Socket Layer" (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communication. Generally, our e-mails are not secure. If we ask you to e-mail us information other than your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, however, it will be obtained using a secure (SSL encryption) e-mail form. 

When you visit our website, you can access site information without revealing your personal identity. In order to help us identify you for future site visits, however, we use "cookies" to track your visit. A "cookie" is a piece of information that our web server stores on your computer hard drive and retrieves later. The cookie will not request, require or collect personal identity information and you remain anonymous. Your customer information is not accessed by, or stored within a cookie in any way. 

**Protecting Children's Information Privacy.**  
Our online financial services are not designed for or directed toward children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children, and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children's identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents. 

**Making Sure Information is Accurate.**  
Keeping your account information accurate and up-to-date is very important. If you ever find that your account information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please contact us at 1-866-4UMPQUA (1-866-486-7782). We will promptly update or correct any erroneous information. 

**Keeping Up-To-Date With Our Privacy Policy.**  
In order to keep our customers up-to-date with our Privacy Policy, we will send you our Privacy Policy annually, as long as you maintain an ongoing relationship with us. We may amend this policy at any time, and we will inform you of changes as required by law. You may have other privacy protections under state laws, and we will comply with applicable state laws when we disclose information about you. You can always review our current policy on our website at: www.umpquabank.com, or contact us for a copy at 1-866-4UMPQUA (1-866-486-7782). 

**Tips to Help You Protect Your Customer Information.**  
If you suspect that someone has had unauthorized access to your account with us, or access to your personal identifying information such as your Social Security number or credit card information, please contact us at 1-866-4UMPQUA (1-866-486-7782) immediately so we can take action to protect you. In addition, you should report the crime to your local law enforcement agency and to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). To speak with a trained FTC telephone counselor, call toll-free at 1-877-IDTHEFT (1-877-438-4338). To enter information about your complaint into a secure FTC online database, sign onto www.consumer.gov/idtheft. This site also provides links to numerous consumer education materials. 

**Privacy Policy Inquiries.**  
If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact us by calling 1-866-4UMPQUA (1-866-486-7782), sending us an e-mail at customerservice@umpquabank.com, or writing to us at Umpqua Bank, Attn: Support Center, P.O. Box 1820, Roseburg, OR 97470. 

|  |
